<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matthieu Gouel</title><link>https://randomlogs.com/</link><description>Recent content on Matthieu Gouel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://randomlogs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zeph &amp; Iris map the internet: A resilient reinforcement learning approach to distributed IP route tracing</title><link>https://randomlogs.com/posts/20220301ccr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://randomlogs.com/posts/20220301ccr/</guid><description>Matthieu Gouel, Kevin Vermeulen, Maxime Mouchet, Justin P. Rohrer, Olivier Fourmaux, Timur Friedman
Representation of the IP-level graph of the internet measured with Iris (credits to Maxime Mouchet).
We describe a new system for distributed tracing at the IP level of the routes that packets take through the IPv4 internet. Our Zeph algorithm coordinates route tracing efforts across agents at multiple vantage points, assigning to each agent a number of /24 destination prefixes in proportion to its probing budget and chosen according to a reinforcement learning heuristic that aims to maximize the number of multipath links discovered.</description></item><item><title>IP Geolocation Database Stability and Implications for Network Research</title><link>https://randomlogs.com/posts/20210914tma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://randomlogs.com/posts/20210914tma/</guid><description>Matthieu Gouel, Kevin Vermeulen, Olivier Fourmaux, Timur Friedman, Robert Beverly
IP geolocation has myriad applications. While a body of prior research has investigated the accuracy of geolocation databases, we take a first look at their stability. Using a large collection of snapshots from a popular geolocation database, we examine the longitudinal evolution of its location mappings and address coverage. Across different classes of IP addresses, we find that significant differences can exist even between two successive weekly snapshots - a previously underappreciated source of potential error.</description></item><item><title>Alias Resolution Based on ICMP Rate Limiting</title><link>https://randomlogs.com/posts/20200201pam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://randomlogs.com/posts/20200201pam/</guid><description>Kevin Vermeulen, Burim Ljuma, Vamsi Addanki, Matthieu Gouel, Olivier Fourmaux, Timur Friedman, Reza Rejaie
Alias resolution techniques (e.g., Midar) associate, mostly through active measurement, a set of IP addresses as belonging to a common router. These techniques rely on distinct router features that can serve as a signature. Their applicability is affected by router support of the features and the robustness of the signature. This paper presents a new alias resolution tool called Limited Ltd.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://randomlogs.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://randomlogs.com/about/</guid><description>Hello! 👋 I&amp;rsquo;m currently a Reseach Fellow at Cloudflare, France.
I recently completed my PhD at Sorbonne Université in Paris, France. My doctoral work is centered on advancing our understanding of the internet infrastructure, achieved through the application of internet-wide high-speed measurements and extensive large-scale analysis. Broadly speaking, my research contributes to addressing challenges across diverse research domains, including network topology and performance, network security, and traffic engineering.
Previously, I held positions as a Software Engineer at the French Ministry for the Armed Forces and as a DevOps Engineer at Société Générale .</description></item></channel></rss>