<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Matthieu Gouel</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Matthieu Gouel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthieugouel.name/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Poster: Towards a Publicly Available Framework to Process Traceroutes with MetaTrace</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20231024imcposter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20231024imcposter/</guid><description>Matthieu Gouel, Omar Darwich, Maxime Mouchet, Kevin Vermeulen
The objective of this research is to contribute towards the development of an open-source framework for processing large-scale traceroute datasets. By providing such a framework, we aim to benefit the community by saving time in everyday traceroute analysis and enabling the design of new scalable reactive measurements, where prior traceroute measurements are leveraged to make informed decisions for future ones. It is important to clarify that our goal is not to surpass proprietary solutions like BigQuery, which are utilized by CDNs for processing billions of traceroutes.</description></item><item><title>Replication: Towards a Publicly Available Internet scale IP Geolocation Dataset</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20231024imcreplication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20231024imcreplication/</guid><description>IP geolocation is one of the most widely used forms of metadata for IP addresses, and despite almost twenty years of effort from the research community, the reality is that there is no accurate, complete, up-to-date, and explainable publicly available dataset for IP geolocation. We argue that a central reason for this state of affairs is the impressive results from prior publications, both in terms of accuracy and coverage: up to street level accuracy and locating millions of IP addresses with a few hundred vantage points in months.</description></item><item><title>Zeph &amp; Iris map the internet: A resilient reinforcement learning approach to distributed IP route tracing</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20220301ccr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20220301ccr/</guid><description>Matthieu Gouel, Kevin Vermeulen, Maxime Mouchet, Justin P. Rohrer, Olivier Fourmaux, Timur Friedman
Representation of the IP-level graph of the internet measured with Iris (credits to Maxime Mouchet).
We describe a new system for distributed tracing at the IP level of the routes that packets take through the IPv4 internet. Our Zeph algorithm coordinates route tracing efforts across agents at multiple vantage points, assigning to each agent a number of /24 destination prefixes in proportion to its probing budget and chosen according to a reinforcement learning heuristic that aims to maximize the number of multipath links discovered.</description></item><item><title>IP Geolocation Database Stability and Implications for Network Research</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20210914tma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20210914tma/</guid><description>Matthieu Gouel, Kevin Vermeulen, Olivier Fourmaux, Timur Friedman, Robert Beverly
IP geolocation has myriad applications. While a body of prior research has investigated the accuracy of geolocation databases, we take a first look at their stability. Using a large collection of snapshots from a popular geolocation database, we examine the longitudinal evolution of its location mappings and address coverage. Across different classes of IP addresses, we find that significant differences can exist even between two successive weekly snapshots - a previously underappreciated source of potential error.</description></item><item><title>Alias Resolution Based on ICMP Rate Limiting</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20200201pam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20200201pam/</guid><description>Kevin Vermeulen, Burim Ljuma, Vamsi Addanki, Matthieu Gouel, Olivier Fourmaux, Timur Friedman, Reza Rejaie
Alias resolution techniques (e.g., Midar) associate, mostly through active measurement, a set of IP addresses as belonging to a common router. These techniques rely on distinct router features that can serve as a signature. Their applicability is affected by router support of the features and the robustness of the signature. This paper presents a new alias resolution tool called Limited Ltd.</description></item></channel></rss>