<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>poster on Matthieu Gouel</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/tags/poster/</link><description>Recent content in poster on Matthieu Gouel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthieugouel.name/tags/poster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Poster: Towards a Publicly Available Framework to Process Traceroutes with MetaTrace</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20231024imcposter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20231024imcposter/</guid><description>Matthieu Gouel, Omar Darwich, Maxime Mouchet, Kevin Vermeulen
The objective of this research is to contribute towards the development of an open-source framework for processing large-scale traceroute datasets. By providing such a framework, we aim to benefit the community by saving time in everyday traceroute analysis and enabling the design of new scalable reactive measurements, where prior traceroute measurements are leveraged to make informed decisions for future ones. It is important to clarify that our goal is not to surpass proprietary solutions like BigQuery, which are utilized by CDNs for processing billions of traceroutes.</description></item><item><title>Replication: Towards a Publicly Available Internet scale IP Geolocation Dataset</title><link>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20231024imcreplication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://matthieugouel.name/posts/20231024imcreplication/</guid><description>IP geolocation is one of the most widely used forms of metadata for IP addresses, and despite almost twenty years of effort from the research community, the reality is that there is no accurate, complete, up-to-date, and explainable publicly available dataset for IP geolocation. We argue that a central reason for this state of affairs is the impressive results from prior publications, both in terms of accuracy and coverage: up to street level accuracy and locating millions of IP addresses with a few hundred vantage points in months.</description></item></channel></rss>